iscglobal.org 2017-02-15

# Privacy Policy | LuxSci

Version 2016.09.01

Lux Scientiae, Incorporated (collectively, "We", "Our", "Us", "LuxSci", or "Lux Scientiae") has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website, [luxsci.com](https://luxsci.com/), and our services in general. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here in this policy, by email, or by means of a notice on our LuxSci FYI Blog prior to the change becoming effective.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Lux Scientiae complies with the U.S.—Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from Switzerland. Lux Scientiae has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Lux Scientiae's certification, please visit [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/). 

## EU—U.S. Privacy Shield

Lux Scientiae participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Lux Scientiae is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework's applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's [Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). 

Lux Scientiae is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Lux Scientiae complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions. 

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Lux Scientiae is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Lux Scientiae may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [https://www.privacyshield.gov], you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

## General usage

While visiting the Lux Scientiae web site, information is stored in log files for the purpose of analyzing what pages are accessed, which files are downloaded, and what errors occur. This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We review which top domain addresses visit our site. This process does not collect any personal information about you or your business. 

When you complete any form on our site including personal information such as your name, addresses, email, phone numbers, and other information, your information is written to a secure file or database and/or emailed to our staff. We will respond to your inquiry if applicable. 

We collect the names, addresses, phone numbers, credit card numbers, and email addresses of our users in order to identify them and provide billing and support services.

## Tracking Technologies

We, Lux Scientiae and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or online chat service providers, use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users' movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis.

We use cookies for our shopping cart, to remember users' settings (e.g. language preference), and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our public website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited.

### HTML5 Local Storage

We use Local Storage (LS) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSs.

### Behavioral Targeting

We partner with a third party ad network to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) and [Here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. 

### Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to "opt-out" of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form. 

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at "support **@** LuxSci.com". We offer an opportunity to opt-out of certain communications on our personal profile update pages, or you may contact us at 1-800-441-6612, "support **@** LuxSci.com", or Lux Scientiae, 15 Brook Street, Medfield, MA 02052 USA.

### OpenID

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

Additionally, we record all logins to Lux Scientiae by our members and the pages visited by them. This is for security purposes and for the purpose of analyzing what pages and features are being used and with what frequency.

### Social Media (Features) and Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as Twitter, Facebook, Google+, a RSS Blog Feed, Widgets, a "Share This" button and interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

## Payments

All payments to Lux Scientiae are made securely online via credit card or PayPal or offline via check, wire transfer, or direct deposit. After you have made a credit card payment, we keep your billing address in our secure database to facilitate future payments. We do not keep any record of your credit card number unless you authorize us to bill you automatically each month. In this case, your credit card information is stored in a PCI-compliant way, not on Lux Scientiae's servers.

## Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). To learn more about SSL, follow this link [How Does Secure Socket Layer (SSL or TLS) Work?]

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## Tell-A-Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to email a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Lux Scientiae stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. 

Your friend may contact us at support **@** LuxSci.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

## Links to Other Sites

If you click on a link to a third party site, you will leave the Lux Scientiae site you are visiting and go to the site you selected. Because we cannot control the activities of third parties, we cannot accept responsibility for any use of your personally identifiable information by such third parties, and we cannot guarantee that they will adhere to the same privacy practices as Lux Scientiae. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of any other service provider from whom you request services. If you visit a third party website that is linked to an Lux Scientiae site, you should read that site's privacy statement before providing any personally identifiable information. 

## Updating / Accessing / Amending / Correcting Personally Identifiable Information

Upon request Lux Scientiae will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. To request this information please login to your account and make this request via a Support Ticket. If you no longer have an account, please use our Contact Form.

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service and would like to have your personally identifiable information deleted, you may update it by making the change on our member profile page or by making a support ticket, or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within 1 day. You can change your personal information online by logging into your "member portal", under "Account > My profile". 

## Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at "support **@** LuxSci.com". We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Agents/Service Providers

We use other third parties such as a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services, a customer service provider that hosts our live chat, and data center providers to provide the servers on which our live services reside. When you sign up for services such as Premium Email Filtering, Email Archival, SSL Certificates, DNS Service, Domain and Registration, we may share your name, physical address, and email address as necessary for the third party to provide that service. 

These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for promotional purposes. 

## Import Contacts

We provide an import contacts feature to help you keep in touch with your contacts by importing your existing contact list into your address books while you are logged into your portal account. 

When logged into the portal, third party personal information may be entered such as name, email, address, and other personal information. This information is only used for the purpose it is collected for. 

## Non-disclosure

Lux Scientiae will not release any information about its clients to third parties without the clients' explicit consent, except as required for compliance with local, state, and federal law or as further set forth below. 

In certain situations, Lux Scientiae may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial or bankruptcy proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site. If Lux Scientiae is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

If you use a bulletin board, blog, or chat room on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. Testimonials are also posted on our site and users have given permission to have their personal information submitted in these testimonials. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. To request removal of your personal information from these public areas of our site, contact us at privacy-officer **@** LuxSci.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. Alternatively, if you used a third party application to post such information, you may be able to remove it by either logging into the said application and removing the information or by contacting the appropriate third party application. 

Some of our blogs (e.g. LuxSci Status) are managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want your personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy statement.

For Customers using Legacy Basic Dedicated Physical Servers and Legacy Shared Business Class Hosting: 

> The Lux Scientiae Acceptable Use Policies specifically prohibit the use of our service for illegal activities. Therefore, you agree that Lux Scientiae may disclose any and all of your information including assigned IP numbers, account history, account use, etc. to any law enforcement agent who makes a verified written request, without further consent or notification to you. LuxSci, or its Basic Server Provider Partners, will verify the legitimacy and authenticity of any such request and determine if compliance with the request is required by local, state, or federal law or if, in its sole discretion, the request should be filled even if it is not required by local, state, or federal law. In addition, Lux Scientiae shall have the right to suspend or terminate all services, at its sole discretion, during such a legal investigation.

For all other Customers:

> You agree that Lux Scientiae may disclose any and all of your information including assigned IP numbers, account history, account use, etc. to any law enforcement agent who makes a verified written request, without further consent or notification to you. LuxSci will verify the legitimacy and authenticity of any such request and determine if compliance with the request is required by local, state, or federal law. Only if the request is verified and compliance is required will the request be filled. In addition, Lux Scientiae shall have the right to suspend or terminate all services, at its sole discretion, during such a legal investigation.

Lux Scientiae does not give out its client's email addresses or send SPAM. Lux Scientiae may occasionally send important announcements regarding Lux Scientiae services to its clients if they have not opted out of this notification service.

For Customers that have a valid HIPAA Business Associate Agreement (BAA) with Lux Scientiae, in the event of a conflict or inconsistency between the terms of this nondisclosure policy and those of the BAA, the terms of the BAA shall prevail.

## Confidentiality

Lux Scientiae staff will not examine the following classes of data without Customer's explicit consent:

  1. Email: The content of sent and received email messages, with the exception of the message metadata including: sender address, recipient addresses, message subject, message size, message id, IP address of the sending or connecting computers, and any message header information removed from messages for the purposes of outbound message anonymization. 
  2. WebAides: The content of all WebAides, including comments and attachments 
  3. Widgets: The content of all Widgets, except the content of custom or third party widgets that is defined directly as part of the widget definition. 
  4. Databases: The content of all databases hosted by Customer in its web hosting account. 
  5. Files: The content of all files saved to the Customers web/FTP space, except as they may otherwise be publicly accessible on the Internet via Customer's web site. Note that this covers only the content of the files, not the list of what files are present and what directories they are located in. 

Information that does not fall within the above classes of data (i.e. email message metadata) will still be kept in the strictest confidence in accordance with Lux Scientiae's non-disclosure policy.

Exception 1: in a case where Lux Scientiae becomes aware of evidence of a possible violation by a client of its Acceptable Use Policy and it concludes that analysis of data is necessary in order to determine the facts, in order to prevent the sending of SPAM, Unsolicited Email, excessive utilization of system resources, or other violations of LuxSci's AUPs, Lux Scientiae will examine such client's data solely for such purpose. The contents of client's data will be kept in the strictest confidence in accordance with Lux Scientiae's non-disclosure policy. 

Exception 2: from time to time Lux Scientiae may audit High Volume Outbound Email customers' bulk email practices. As stated in the High Volume AUP (HVAUP), Lux Scientiae can and will store and/or review the content of any or all outbound email messages sent via the High Volume service to ensure compliance with the High Volume Email Restrictions (see the HVAUP). 

Exception 3: for Customers that have a valid HIPAA Business Associate Agreement (BAA) with Lux Scientiae, in the event of a conflict or inconsistency between the terms of this confidentiality policy and those of the BAA, the terms of the BAA shall prevail.

## Medical privacy (HIPAA)

Clients that are legally required to abide by the regulations of HIPAA (i.e. HIPAA Covered Entities and Business Associates of HIPAA Covered Entities, namely, (1) health plans, (2) health care clearinghouses, or (3) health care providers who electronically transmit any health information in connection with transactions for which the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services has adopted standards), Lux Scientiae has the following Addendum to its Master Services Agreement (MSA). This is the "Business Associate Agreement" required for HIPAA compliance between Lux Scientiae, as the "Business Associate", and the Client, as the "Covered Entity". 

Due to the Security and Privacy restrictions imposed by the BAA and by HIPAA that are not required for other types of accounts, this Addendum is not automatically incorporated into new or existing Lux Scientiae accounts. If you require a BAA with Lux Scientiae, please print out and sign the BAA and Account Restrictions Agreement using the links below and return them to Lux Scientiae for review and acceptance. LUX SCIENTIAE WILL NOT BE DEEMED A BUSINESS ASSOCIATE OF ANY CUSTOMER FOR PURPOSES OF HIPAA UNLESS AND UNTIL A SIGNED ADDENDUM IS RECEIVED, REVIEWED, AND ACCEPTED BY THE LUX SCIENTIAE HIPAA PRIVACY OFFICER.

  * Standard Lux Scientiae HIPAA Agreements

You may return signed versions of these documents to Lux Scientiae by:

  * Using the Online Signature Form
  * Faxing to 413-332-0598 
  * Emailing to: support AT LuxSci.com 
  * Mailing to Lux Scientiae at 15 Brook Street, Medfield, MA 02052 USA 
  * Scanning and attaching digital copies to a support ticket in your Lux Scientiae account.
